{
  "reference_number": "1632",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Emissions - Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050",
      "answer_index": 1,
      "notes": "Net zero emissions is needed. We need to take a radical step if we want the world to follow suit. Our image is a clean green country,\n so the world will take notice of us. We have spent far too much time sitting around waiting for someone to do something. We need to\n make a drastic change NOW."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "No, the only change that should effect this is if situations worsen, and we need to bring the deadline closer."
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The government needs to invest in startups and established firms which will make a difference, such as companies developing\n\n electric cars, solar power etc. Provide larger government grants to impact investors who will do this. We need to work towards\n creating better alternatives (eg electric cars), rather than restricting use (eg. massive petrol taxes, although these are a good way to\n\n raise this extra capital, to a point)."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Act as a stand alone entity, such as the reserve bank. With its sole goal being to reduce emissions AA WELL AS net emissions."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Makes decisions itself in respect of the number of units available in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 10,
      "notes": "As above, \"Act as a stand alone entity, such as the reserve bank. With its sole goal being to reduce emissions AA WELL AS net\nemissions.\" It should operate independently, removed from politics."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Absolutely. Increase the consumers awareness to help them make informed decisions with their purchases. Most people don't want\n\nglobal warming, but feel powerless as they do no know what steps to take. This will help the everyman to make a positive difference."
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Impact investing is the key. We must provide better alternatives to the environment damaging goods we are accustomed to. large\n\nestablished corporates will likely not not make a moral shift, they will only change their ways if their consumers start buying more\nenvironmentally friendly goods. For consumers to do this, there must be better alternatives available, and for this to happen, impact\ninvesting is the solution, from a government to private investing levels.\n\n\n\n\n You have elected to withhold your personal details from publication."
    }
  ]
}
